A NETFLIX SERIES
[dramatic music playing]
Well, I had given everyone
an exercise to do in class.
An autobiographic story.
I asked them to tell me about
an important event that happened to them.
It's a difficult exercise for me.
I like making stories up,
but I don't like
talking about myself so much.
[sighs]
The girl was struggling.
She didn't feel well.
I was very flustered.
Uh, at a certain point
I couldn't take it anymore,
so I... I left the classroom
and went to the bathroom.
She looked really startled.
I wanted to make sure
it was nothing serious.
Then what happened?
Then he followed me into the bathroom.
Then I went in and asked
how she was doing, if she was okay.
And then?
I leaned against the sink.
I could barely breathe.
I couldn't get myself to calm down.
The girl that saw you together
said that you were very close.
That you were hugging.
[Carlo] No.
No. We weren't hugging.
I knew I was going to pass out.
Uh, so yeah,
the professor was holding me up.
When I got closer,
she closed her eyes
and, um, fell into my arms.
That's all.
It's different.
Uh, it's not what I would call hugging.
Do you have anything to report
about Professor Pentecoste's behavior?
What do you mean?
[man] Has he ever shown
special interest towards you?
No.
Have you ever seen the girl
outside of university?
No.
I mean, only during our individual
meetings as part of the program.
He just encouraged me to write.
We get along very well.
He's an excellent professor.
The university's reputation is at stake.
As well as yours, naturally.
That's why I wanted to clear things up
and discard any ambiguities.
Nothing happened in the bathroom.
I just wanted to help her.
[exhales]
Whatever has been said...
- It was just a big misunderstanding.
- A big misunderstanding.
[door closes]
[music fades]
[keys jangling]
[sighs]
[pan sizzling]
- I'm home.
- [Margherita] Hey!
What happened?
Are we celebrating something?
No. I just had some free time.
And so you decided to cook, huh?
A little bit. Yeah.
Something very, very, very smoky?
No.
- What?
- Hmm?
Oh shit! The zucchinis!
- [Margherita] No!
- [Carlo] What?
No. Go sit down. Sit down.
[dish clattering]
[Margherita] Whatever.
Okay. So couscous with mint,
salmon, and cherry tomatoes.
Mmm!
There's also the zucchini,
but they didn't make it.
[Carlo chuckles]
Looks good.
- Now try it and let me know.
- [Carlo clears throat]
Be honest. Okay?
Mmm.
- You don't like it?
- Mmm. It's good.
It's exotic.
I can tell you don't like it.
- You're a terrible liar. No. You don't.
- [Carlo] I do.
[Carlo chuckles]
[Margherita] Listen...
I have something to tell you.
Me too.
Tell me.
[Carlo sighs]
Something happened at the university.
What?
A girl didn't feel well
during an exercise in class.
She had a sort of a panic attack.
[breathes deeply]
I was in the hallway,
and I saw her go into the bathroom.
I followed her to...
to see how she was, to help her.
[tense music playing]
And she practically collapsed in my arms.
And?
Hmm. Nothing. I held her up.
But a girl saw us so close together
she misinterpreted it.
What do you mean?
[Carlo] I don't know.
I don't know what she...
what she... she might have thought,
we were very close.
- [Margherita] When did this happen?
- Yesterday.
And you didn't tell me?
[Carlo] I didn't think it was important.
Then this morning, the dean
called us into his office, and so...
How close were you?
Honey, she fainted.
She fainted. She wasn't feeling well.
What else could I do?
Nothing.
- You don't believe me.
- [Margherita] Yeah. I do.
Of course.
And what did the dean say?
- Did he believe you?
- [Carlo] Yeah. He did.
- Did you get into trouble?
- [Carlo] No, no.
No. Like I said,
we, uh... we cleared it all up.
Okay.
And you?
What did you wanna tell me?
No. Nothing. I, um...
Just that I might be able
to close on a... a new offer.
- [Carlo] Hmm.
- Hmm.
- [Carlo] Great.
- Yep.
It's good. Yeah.
[light switch clicks]
[Carlo breathes deeply]
Are you happy?
What kind of question is that?
Of course I'm happy.
What's that girl's name?
[sighs]
Are you jealous?
[chuckles]
Sofia is her name.
Sofia Casadei.
Have you been talking?
[exhales] Come on, Marghe.
Do you get along with her?
[sighs]
Sweetie, nothing happened.
Okay?
I just felt
like I had to help her. That's it.
Really?
So what did you do? Did you...
[melancholy music playing]
...comfort her?
Hmm?
- Uh, well...
- Professor.
She seems like a very fragile girl.
[both breathing heavily]
I'm fragile too.
Very fragile.
[both breathing heavily]
SOFIA CASADEI
STUDENT NO. 133521
[Margherita] "I thought I knew you.
I knew your sadness.
Your dark days.
You held your dreams captive
deep in your soul.
I could see it in your eyes.
But you were smiling that day.
We played together. We listened to a song.
You took me with you.
You wanted to take me
to where your love was born.
I couldn't tell
where you were actually taking me."
[tense music playing]
[discordant music swelling]
[car horn honks]
[car engine revving]
I really don't know
how it could've happened.
Ugh. Unbelievable!
Obviously, we didn't take it down.
No. Look.
But... Good grief!
Of course the house is still for sale!
No, ma'am. Listen.
We'll do this. I'll fix it now.
I'll fix it, then I'll call you...
I'll call you as soon as possible. Okay?
Thanks.
I'll call you back soon.
- The owner of Concordia.
- Mrs. Di Benedetto?
[Eva] Someone took
the sign off the building.
Really?
It's fine. Okay. Let's fix this.
Ugh.
What about you, honey?
How are you? Are you doing okay?
Yeah. Just a bit of a headache today.
Are you nauseous?
- A little bit.
- Do you have swollen feet?
Ugh. Eva, come on!
I'm not pregnant.
If it means that much to you,
then you get pregnant.
I'd rather be drowned.
Listen. I'll take care of the sign. Okay?
- [Eva] Really? Thanks, honey.
- Sure.
What happened
to the two people that wanted to buy it?
Well, they changed their mind.
Bummer. We almost closed it.
I know.
- [Eva] Okay. So you're taking care of it?
- Yep. Yeah, yeah.
[Eva] Thanks.
- Bye.
- Ciao.
[footsteps receding]
[door opening]
[girl] Hi.
Whoa!
[dramatic music playing]
[keyboard clacking]
[cell phone chimes]
SOFIA: HI, CARLO
I'M WRITING. I NEED YOUR HELP.
WHEN CAN WE MEET?
[sighs]
- Hey.
- [Carlo] Hey, honey.
[door closes]
How are you?
Not bad.
I haven't cooked yet. I'm sorry.
It's been one of those days
where nothing gets done.
Don't worry about it.
[tense music playing]
[breathes deeply]
Hey, Hemingway.
Get ready. I'm taking you out.
Okay.
Wow!
And he just talks our ears off.
He just talks and talks and talks.
Just shut up, Luca! Shut up! Dammit!
Listen. You could invite him
to the symposium.
- What? Come on. You're not...
- He's the perfect guest.
Thanks. That's mine.
Well, time for a toast,
but I should do it now 'cause
it's our third round, so it's my turn.
[Carlo] What are we toasting to?
Let's toast to, um,
to the perfect crime.
- Oh. Is that so?
- [chuckles lightly]
[Carlo] Who's dead?
- No one, yet.
[Carlo] Mm.
What did you do?
[house music playing]
[indistinct chatter]
I took it off the market.
Concordia?
Mm-hmm.
I didn't sell it to them,
and I removed the ad.
Does the owner know?
- No.
- No?
[both laugh]
I know, it's crazy.
So, what's the plan now?
So, now the plan is
to convince the owner to lower the price
or the apartment will never sell.
And then we wait for her to lower it,
and when the right time comes,
we make our offer.
You are diabolical.
- You think?
- [Carlo] Yeah.
You're a bad, bad girl.
- So bad.
- Mmm.
We're gonna go home and deal with you.
Why at home?
[door creaks]
[house music muffles]
[both chuckle]
[Carlo moans]
[both breathing heavily]
[moaning]
- Oh!
- Oh. Sorry!
- Shit! No!
- [laughing]
No.
It was... it was open.
Oh, I can't believe it! [laughs]
Do you think it's normal? I mean...
Is it normal
to have a bathroom without a lock?
[Margherita] Did you see
the look on his face?
- Yeah. I saw it. Yeah.
- [Margherita laughing]
Anyway, I told you
we should've gone home, huh?
- Oh, really?
- Yeah.
So, you're saying you didn't like my idea?
- No, no. It was a lot of fun. Yeah.
- Yeah?
Honey, I'm driving.
The last thing we need
is to get pulled over.
[cell phone ringing]
- Answer it.
- Why would she call me so late?
SOFIA CASADEI
ACCEPT, DECLINE
Answer it.
Hello, Sofia?
How are you? You okay?
[Sofia] Yeah. I mean, I don't know.
I... I wanted to talk to you.
Talk to me?
[Sofia] I sent you a text. Did you see it?
No, no. I... I didn't see it.
It's late. Sofia, it's almost midnight.
I'm in the car here with my wife,
and you're on speaker.
[Sofia] Uh, sorry.
I didn't realize it was so late.
All right. You can tell me
what's up tomorrow. Okay?
[Sofia] Okay. Goodnight.
Goodnight.
Stop the car.
- [sighs] But we're almost there.
- I said stop the car!
[tires screech]
[Carlo] Where are you going?
Where are you go... Marghe? Where...
- [car door closes]
- Goddamnit!
[parking brake ratchets]
[car door closes]
[siren wailing]
Marghe, what are you doing? You smoke now?
[Margherita] Leave me alone. Okay?
[Carlo] Honey, please.
I know it bothered you, but don't make
a bigger deal of this than it is.
"Don't make a bigger deal
than it is," Carlo?
You think this is normal?
She's calling you
at midnight and it's fine?
- [Carlo] You heard the call.
- Yeah. I heard.
Yeah. So... so you saw
that I've got nothing to hide.
- You told her she was on speaker. No?
- So, what?
It's not exactly what someone
with nothing to hide would do.
I wanted to make her understand
that it's late, I'm married,
and that she can't call me
whenever she wants.
[scoffs] What a man!
I can't believe
we're fighting over this shit right now.
She's 20, Marghe.
She's 20. It's okay
for her to call people this late.
- Really? How do you know?
- [Carlo] Yeah.
I don't know. I don't know. I imagine so.
You're so full of shit!
- [Carlo] Please. Let's go.
- Do you talk outside of class?
- [Carlo] No. We don't talk. No.
- No. But she writes to you. Texts. Calls.
- [Carlo] Enough!
- Are you seeing each other?
- [Carlo] No!
- Tell me.
[Carlo] We're drunk. We drank too much.
It's cold. Look. You're even shaking.
Please, let's go home. Come on.
[Margherita scoffs]
[melancholy music playing]
[car door closes]
- [liquid pouring]
- [silverware clattering]
[Carlo sighs]
[inhales deeply]
I'm going to bed.
Are you coming?
What happened in that bathroom?
Nothing.
- [Margherita] Did you fuck?
- Marghe.
- [Margherita] Tell me.
- No.
We didn't fuck.
I told you the truth. What else can I do?
How can I prove to you
that nothing happened?
You're right. You can't.
Okay. I'm going.
What about you? You staying home?
I'll go to the office later.
I have an appointment at ten.
- Have a good day.
- Ciao.
[door closes]
[tense music playing]
UCM - UNIVERSITY
FOR THE CREATIVE ARTS MILAN
[tense music continues]
[indistinct chatter]
Just ten minutes!
Everybody back in ten. Okay?
Sofia.
Sorry about yesterday.
I wanted to ask you for some advice,
but I could've waited until today.
But, uh, I'm not very good
at waiting it seems.
[Carlo] You just need
to believe in yourself more.
You don't need any more advice.
I want it from you, though.
I don't want things to change between us.
[dramatic music playing]
[inaudible]
[tense music playing]
I'm here for you. Always will be.
But you have to learn
to stand on your own two feet. Okay?
Okay.
Hey!
Everything okay?
- Yeah.
- [Carlo] What are you doing here?
You need to be more careful.
Antihistamines.
You always forget them.
You're right.
Luckily, I have you.
- [Margherita] See you tonight.
- Okay.
[footsteps receding]
[indistinct chatter]
[dramatic music playing]
[Andrea] How's it going?
Today? Bad.
Worse than usual.
Turn around.
[Andrea exhales]
Will massaging my back
relieve the pain in my leg?
You really don't trust anyone. Do you?
[exhales]
[Andrea] Stop thinking.
Can you do that?
No.
I can't do that.
I simply can't.
Yes. You can.
What did you find?
Oh, Portraits of a Marriage.
[Carlo] Yours or Franco's?
Franco's? Are you kidding?
He wouldn't waste a minute
on anything other than comic books.
No, no.
Márai is one of my true favorites.
"Most people don't know how to love
or how to let themselves be loved,
because they're either cowards or proud,
or because they fear failure."
- [chuckles] What a book. Wonderful, huh?
- [Carlo] Hmm.
- Can I ask you a question, Anna?
- [Anna] Of course.
Do you and Franco
tell each other everything?
Only the good stuff.
You? What do you have to say?
[exhales] Hmm.
Never noticed that stain.
[Anna] Oh, yes.
[chuckles] It's been there for a while.
I already called the painter.
Now I just need to empty the studio
and pack up the boxes.
If you want, I can help.
No, no, no.
Don't worry. I'll do it myself.
Oh. Listen, Carlo.
I won't be here next Thursday.
Okay.
- See you the Thursday after?
- Mm.
And then we can talk about
what you don't want to tell me today.
I don't wanna tell you anything.
[Anna chuckles]
[Carlo] Can I borrow this?
Of course.
But don't let Margherita know
about it. Okay?
'Cause if she sees you reading that book,
uh, it might get a little tense.
[both chuckle lightly]
- [jazz music playing]
- [indistinct chatter]
[Margherita] Thanks.
- Oh!
- [woman] Here she is!
[Margherita laughs]
- Hi!
- [woman] You look great, huh?
Honey, everything's amazing, really.
- Thanks.
- I'm so proud of you.
Thanks, but I can't relax just yet.
Oh, come on. You have to relax.
I've only heard positive things.
- [woman] Well, he's a genius.
- [Margherita] Yeah.
And to think he did it all
with just a ballpoint pen.
- The whole drawing...
- Giulia? Achille is here.
- Hi, Margherita.
- [Margherita] Hi, Alice.
See you later.
[Giulia] What did he say?
- [man] She looks like you.
- [Margherita] What?
[man] The woman in the painting.
You think?
He's holding her in his arms, but
she's looking elsewhere.
Like you.
You're here with all these people,
but you seem...
so distant.
Marcello.
[chuckles]
Margherita.
What do you do for a living, Margherita?
I'm a real estate agent.
But?
"But?"
[Marcello chuckles]
That look is back again.
The distant look.
I'm actually an architect, and I wanna...
I wanted to be an interior designer.
And why did you give it up?
Life is full of choices.
I didn't mean to make you uncomfortable.
You didn't make me uncomfortable.
Are you here alone?
Not really. No.
Is he your fiancé?
Husband.
[chuckles]
What about you?
What do you do for a living?
And what about your dreams?
Have they all come true?
[chuckles]
I don't know.
[Alice] Margherita.
Let me introduce you to our artist.
Oh, well,
congratulations!
[Alice] I'm sorry, Marcello.
There's someone I want you to meet.
It's been a great pleasure
to meet you, Margherita.
[man] Seriously?
That's all you have to say to me?
Really? I... I can't believe it.
Unbelievable!
[Giulia] Calm down, Marco.
[Marco] This many years together.
That's all you can say?
[Giulia] Listen to me, Marco.
I can explain. Please listen to me!
[Marco] Do you realize
the shit I had to read?
I'll make you read it
sentence by sentence!
I took it by mistake
because it looks like mine.
But after you realized it was mine...
You shouldn't spy on me!
What the fuck are you saying?
You shouldn't have fucked that guy!
- [Giulia] That's enough.
- [Marco] It's not fucking enough!
- Tell me where...
- [Giulia] Keep it down!
- [Marco] Why'd you do it?
- [Giulia] 'Cause you're stuck, Marco.
We're stuck. We had plans,
but we're not going anywhere!
Hmm?
You're a bitch. You know that?
Yep.
But you know I'm right.
I have to go now.
That's crazy.
Yeah. It's crazy.
Hmm.
From the Maldives to divorce.
What a nice change of plans, huh?
Oh, come on, Carlo. Stop it.
How can you joke about this?
I'm really shocked!
I mean, how did she
hide everything for six months?
She didn't say anything to me,
and I didn't notice anything.
Why did you stop in and see me at school?
What can I do to make you feel better
about things between us?
[tense music playing]
I don't know.
[bus door closes]
[bus squeals]
[cell phone ringing]
Papa?
- [father] Hi! How are you?
- [bell chiming]
I can't hear you!
[father] How are you?
Oh, I'm doing well.
[father] Hmm. Are you sure?
Yeah. Why do you ask? Why wouldn't I be?
[father] Come on. Tell me.
No. It's nothing. I'm just...
There's stuff at school.
I have to do some work
that I'm struggling with.
[father] Oh. See?
I knew there was something.
When are you coming home?
As soon as I can.
[father] Want me to send you
a piadina with squacquerone?
Well...
[father] Oh, that's better.
Don't make me worry about you, please.
And remember
that when something is difficult
it's a good sign
because it... it means you like it.
[tense music playing]
[father] Hello?
Sofia, are you there?
Yeah. Papa, I'll call you back soon. Bye.
[father] Bye, sweetheart. Bye.
[man] You're early! Wow. [chuckles]
Well, I should get a ski pass
'cause it's gonna snow today.
[Sofia] Yeah.
- [man] Good morning.
- Hey there.
Can I come in? Are you closed?
No, no, no. We've just opened.
Have a seat, please.
[Margherita] Thanks.
[man] What can I get you?
We can do a coffee or a smoothie?
[Margherita] A smoothie, please.
[man] Perfect.
Uh, apple, pineapple, and ginger?
- [Margherita] Great. Thanks.
- [man] Right away.
Sofia?
Yes?
Have I met you before?
You know who I am.
How can I help you today?
I'd like to talk to you for a minute,
if that's okay.
Sure.
I'd like to hear your version.
Of what?
[chuckles]
Of what happened
in the university bathroom.
Well, my version's the same
as the, uh... the professor's is.
I wasn't feeling well.
I went to the bathroom, and he helped me.
And then?
And then nothing.
Someone saw us and misunderstood it.
And is there a reason to misunderstand it?
Is this an interrogation?
[scoffs]
I'm sorry.
You're right,
it does kinda seem like an interrogation.
It's just that Carlo and I
have been together for years,
and, um, we have plans for the future,
and I... I have to know the truth.
I just told you everything
that I have to say.
[Margherita] What you have to say
or what you wanna say?
In this case, there's no difference.
So what did you want from my husband
when you called him at midnight?
[Sofia] I didn't realize it was so late.
I was, uh, writing a story,
the assignment that he gave us to turn in.
The autobiography?
Yeah.
And I wanted his help.
Well, Carlo said you're talented.
And that you're a bit stuck.
Persist.
[dishes clanking]
I'll leave you now. I promise.
I'd like to ask you one last question.
Does he have feelings for you?
No.
It seems he already has
everything he wants.
[scoffs]
Thanks.
And sorry, uh...
[exhales]
[tense music playing]
[indistinct chatter]
- Uh, excuse me?
- Yes? Hi.
Hi. Um, I can't remember.
Sofia Casadei. Where...
Yes. Look. There are two girls.
Uh, first balcony, it's the third door.
- Oh, perfect. Thanks.
- [man] Not a problem.
[tense music continues]
[doorbell ringing]
- Hello?
- Hey there.
I'm the real estate agent
for the property's evaluation.
- May I?
- [girl] Sure.
The owner never mentioned this.
Oh,
he must've forgotten.
Does that mean he's looking
to sell the house?
No, no.
It's just a precautionary evaluation.
I need to take some measurements.
It'll take a few minutes.
Yeah. Actually, I was studying, um...
Oh. I'm sorry to bother you.
Mm-hmm.
Is that your room over there?
No. That one's my roommate's.
Oh. Well, so maybe I'll start there
then, so I don't disturb you.
Hmm.
["Myth" by Beach House playing]
[indistinct chatter]
[man] Honey, two coffees, please.
Thanks.
THE WRITING OF TIME
♪ Drifting in and out ♪
♪ You see the road you're on ♪
♪ It came rolling down your cheek ♪
♪ You say just what you mean ♪
♪ And in between... ♪
[cell phone chimes]
Hi, Carlo.
I wanted to let you know I'm leaving.
- [man] Hi, Pentecoste.
- Mario.
- [Mario] You have five minutes?
- [Carlo] Sure.
Listen. I just wanted
to talk to you about...
[cell phone chimes]
You know? Because I own...
So I just wanted to make sure
we come to terms about a certain subject.
♪ If you built yourself a myth ♪
♪ You'd know just what to give ♪
- I'm counting on it.
- Okay.
- Shall we go?
- Sure. Sounds good. Right behind you.
♪ What comes after this? ♪
♪ Momentary bliss ♪
♪ The consequence ♪
[Sofia] Hi, Carlo.
I wanted to let you know I'm leaving.
I'm quitting the course. I'm going home.
I can't take it anymore.
Your wife came to talk to me.
♪ Help me to name it ♪
ONE MAN, ONE WOMAN
BY CARLO PENTECOSTE
A LOVE STORY STUCK HALFWAY
YOU ARE THE FIRST AND ONLY ONE
I'M LETTING READ IT. CARLO
♪ Canyon calling
Would they come to greet you? ♪
♪ Let you know you're not the only one ♪
Pentecoste, are you coming?
Ladies and gentlemen,
please take your seats.
Let's get started.
♪ Can't keep hanging on ♪
♪ To what is dead and gone ♪
♪ If you built yourself a myth ♪
♪ You'd know just what to give ♪
♪ Materialize ♪
♪ Or let the ashes fly ♪
♪ Help me to name it ♪
[inaudible]
[song fades]
[dramatic music playing]
LOOSELY BASED ON "FIDELITY"
BY MARCO MISSIROLI
[music fades]