A NETFLIX SERIES
["Valse Sentimentale no. 6, Op. 51"
by Tchaikovsky playing]
SIX YEARS BEFORE
[doorbell jingling]
[footsteps approaching]
[dishes clanking]
- [man] Hi. A cappuccino.
- [cashier] One-fifty.
- [man] Have a good day.
- [cashier] Thank you.
[doorbell jingling]
[door opening, closing]
[waiter] Good afternoon.
Can I get you something?
An Americano, please.
- [waiter] Sure.
- Thank you.
[dishes clattering]
Hello.
- [woman] A coffee, please.
- [cashier] One euro.
- [woman] Have a nice day.
- [cashier] Thanks.
- [door opens]
- [doorbell jingles]
[indistinct chatter]
- Thank you.
- [waiter] Of course.
- [Carlo] Good morning. I had black coffee.
- [cashier] One euro, please, sir.
[coins jingling]
[cashier] Thank you.
[Carlo sniffs]
[doorbell jingles]
[Margherita] Hey!
Oh, one sec!
I'll be right back.
Excuse me.
Sir, wait!
Hey, sir!
[yells]
[Margherita] Shit! [winces]
Shit!
[groans]
["Valse Sentimentale, no. 6, Op. 51"
by Tchaikovsky ringing on phone]
Who is this?
Hi. I'm, uh, the owner of this phone.
Tchaikovsky!
Nice ringtone.
[Carlo] Wait.
Is this the girl from Bar Basso?
It is.
PLISAR PUBLISHING
Huh.
Well, that's two points for you, I guess.
Why am I getting points?
For one, you recognized Tchaikovsky
from just the first few notes,
and two, because you're not a thief.
[chuckles]
[Carlo] So where can I meet you?
You'll never guess.
[dramatic music playing]
EMERGENCY ROOM
PEDESTRIAN ENTRANCE
- Hey. Hi!
- [Margherita] Hello.
Uh, I'm out here, outside.
Where should I meet you?
[Margherita] Where are you?
Outside at the,
uh... the emergency entrance.
[Margherita] Hmm.
You see all those columns?
[Carlo] Uh, yeah.
- [Margherita] Walk straight ahead.
- Okay.
Have they told you anything?
Are you okay?
[Margherita] Well, it'll be a while
before I can run again,
but I'll survive.
[chuckles]
Listen, uh... So I'm here,
but I don't know where I'm going.
[Margherita] Just keep walking.
Why don't you tell me what room it is?
[Margherita] Just keep going
straight ahead.
[sighs]
So I'm basically
at the end of the path here.
[Margherita] Okay.
Can you see the flowers?
Yes. The flowers, they're right here.
Now what?
I'm at the flowers, where do I go?
Hmm?
[Margherita] Oh, red.
Great choice.
[Carlo] Come on. Where are you?
[Margherita] Look to your left.
It's pretty serious, huh?
You really hurt yourself.
It is. It was someone else's fault too.
Well then, I guess
I'll make it up to you. Okay?
[Margherita] How are you gonna do that?
Way too easy.
I lead you over here to the flowers.
All right.
Let's see what you can come up with.
- Okay.
- [Margherita chuckles]
[inaudible]
Attraction is just a fleeting moment.
Everything is destined to end.
It's a bit of a strong message.
Is that what you think your book's about?
I guess. It is pretty depressing.
No.
Why?
If that's what you wanna say, go ahead.
Just focus in more
on that concept. Okay? Hmm?
Bring me that new draft
next time you come. All right?
[groans]
Thanks. I absolutely will. Thanks again.
- See you soon.
- You bet.
Oh!
[Luca] Oh!
Look who I brought by to see you.
[Carlo] Sofia!
Hey.
[Carlo] How are you?
- [Sofia moans happily]
- How was your trip?
- [Sofia] Fine. I really miss Milan.
- Is your dad with you?
Yes. He went to see the Duomo. [chuckles]
- I'm glad.
- Yes. It's great. Wonderful.
- Aren't you forgetting something?
- Yes! Yes!
Look... look what I have.
The very first copy.
Fresh off the press for you.
[Sofia gasps]
- [Sofia] Oh my gosh. It's amazing!
- Soak it all in.
It won't be your only novel, though.
Well, I hope not.
Exactly right.
- These copies are for you.
- [cell phone ringing]
Excuse me for a minute.
Hi, Anna!
Yeah. We're still on for lunch.
Actually, you know what else?
I'm bringing you another book. A new one.
On sale, tomorrow.
[upbeat music playing]
[footsteps approaching]
[both panting]
How far are we?
Just under six kilometers.
[Andrea] And... stop!
[both panting]
We needed that.
Brush off all the tension.
[Andrea] Everything's ready
for tonight, right?
It is.
No need to worry, then.
I'll see you around 7:00,
unless, uh, you need more time?
No, eight. seven is too early.
I'll never be ready by then.
That's a friend of mine. I'm gonna say hi.
- Okay.
- See you tonight.
[exhales sharply]
[breathing heavily]
[cell phone ringing]
Carlo?
- [Carlo] Hi.
- Hey.
Mom.
Are you okay? What's going on?
Ugh. I hurt my leg. I ran into the table.
It's terrible.
Imagine if Carlo hadn't been there.
[Carlo] I spoke to the surgeon.
The fracture's displaced,
but it's nothing serious.
He said the operation's really standard.
[sighs] So they're operating?
I can't expect this to heal itself.
[doctor] All right, ma'am. Are you ready?
- [Anna groans]
- All right. Excuse me.
Let's go, let's go. Huh.
- Bye, Anna.
- See you, Carlo.
Bye, sweetheart.
I'll be here, okay?
[breathes deeply]
I'm not moving.
Carlo, thanks.
Well, of course.
[dramatic music playing]
How you doing?
I'm well.
And you?
I'm good.
If you don't mind,
I'd love to be here for the operation.
Sure.
SURGICAL UNIT
NO ENTRY
Thanks.
[Carlo inhales deeply] You're welcome.
[indistinct chatter]
So you were having lunch with my mother?
Yeah.
You know, we have lunch from time to time.
We don't talk about you.
[laughs]
Sorry. I had better respond
to this message.
Yeah. Go ahead.
[cell phone chimes]
Hi, Eva. I'm still in the hospital
waiting on Mom's operation.
It's nothing serious,
but I need to wait here.
Could you please just
let all of the guests on your list know
that the opening is being postponed,
but we'll let them know soon?
Thanks again.
[cell phone chimes]
Finally opening your own studio.
[chuckles]
- So she does tell you things.
- Well...
[chuckles]
I actually knew about the project,
but not that today was the official start.
Well, I hear
that you've been making big improvements.
So I suppose she told you
a few things about me?
[chuckles]
That's all she said. [chuckles]
[footsteps approaching]
[Marcello] Margherita.
[Margherita] Hi.
How's your mom doing?
She's in surgery,
but luckily it's nothing serious.
- [Marcello] That's good.
- [Margherita] Yeah.
Marcello, this is Carlo.
- Hi. Nice to meet you.
- Hi.
Well...
I better go.
- Thanks for everything, Carlo.
- Of course.
- Let me know how she's doing.
- [Margherita] Of course.
Bye.
And you? How are you?
I'm fine, fine.
Uh, I'm a little bit nervous, but...
I hope it all goes well.
Of course. Do you need anything?
Can I do anything?
[Margherita] No. That's okay.
Thank you for coming.
[melancholy music playing]
How are you feeling, Mom?
[groans] Just perky.
[chuckles]
I'm sorry that this ruined your event.
No.
The important thing
is that you're doing better.
My party will wait.
Are you kidding? No.
You're going to have it tomorrow!
I want you to be there too.
Margherita,
don't wait for me.
In fact, it's important
your business opens, and don't argue.
[dramatic music playing]
You can go now, sweetheart.
I'm fine. Go on.
I need some rest.
- I'll see you tomorrow.
- [Anna] Mm.
Hey. Will you bring that book by Buzzati?
Of course.
[both blow kisses]
[cell phone ringing]
Carlo, hi!
Yes. The surgery went smoothly.
Everything's just fine.
Oh. What did I say?
Nothing to worry about. See?
Now, just a little physical therapy
and then you'll be back
on your feet before you know it.
Yeah.
[chuckles] Sure.
Is she with you?
No. Poor thing. I made her go and rest.
She was beat.
Okay.
Well then, Anna, get some rest.
Have a good night. Call you tomorrow.
[groans] Have a good night, Carlo.
Thank you.
Oh!
What's going on in here?
I mean, where did all your clothes go?
[girl chuckles]
[Carlo moans]
[Carlo chuckles]
- [light switch clicks]
- [door closes]
Are you hungry? We could order something.
Hmm. I'm not hungry.
Honestly, I'm exhausted.
Of course. I know this has all been a lot.
But everything's okay now.
Yes. You're right.
Want me to stay with you tonight?
It's up to you.
I'll be passed out
any minute, though. [chuckles]
[laughs] Well, it's your house,
so it's up to you.
Come on.
You're staying here.
[dramatic music playing]
I had a good time.
Me too.
You know,
you could sleep here if you want.
[girl] That's okay.
I'd rather be in my own bed.
Okay.
[chuckles]
Bye.
WHEN WE STOP PLAYING
PREMIO CAMPIELLO
CARLO PENTECOSTE,
FROM WRITER TO TALENT SCOUT
SOFIA CASADEI AND HER NOVEL
THE WAY THINGS ARE
WILL BE PRESENTED TOMORROW
BY CARLO PENTECOSTE
How was it seeing her again?
[both chuckling]
How is she doing?
She's doing really well.
A little too well.
- Too well?
- Hmm.
Yep.
I mean, she looked amazing.
Even more beautiful
than when she was with me.
To me, she's changed.
- [Marco] How so?
- Well, um...
She seems stronger.
Her expression was different.
I mean, do you think
maybe at this exact moment
she's talking about
how good she that thought you looked?
[Giulia] How was he? Hmm?
- [Margherita] Normal.
- I knew it.
Same shirt and glasses, huh?
Yeah. Just normal. He seemed good.
So you were looking at him?
- Of course I was. He was there.
- [Giulia giggles]
Anyway, it was strange.
- What do you mean?
- [Margherita] It was strange. Don't know.
It's like that with exes.
Strange, you know?
- Yeah.
- Well, what did you say to each other?
[jazz music playing]
Nothing really.
He was really kind. That was nice.
- Oh. I mean, that's good. Right?
- [chuckles]
What was he supposed to do? Attack her?
He stayed with her at the hospital.
He didn't have to.
- [Margherita chuckles]
- Hey. Wasn't Marcello there?
- Oh. You were surrounded.
- [Margherita scoffs]
- And you loved it!
- Stop it!
[all laughing]
You know what the fucked up part is?
I was with her
the night they first saw each other.
What night was that?
Uh, at the gallery's opening night.
[gasps] Okay.
It was a nice night.
I can remember it all now.
A very passionate evening.
Anyway...
By the way, for my personal taste,
I think his work is a little...
Look. I don't fucking understand it.
What the hell is it supposed to be?
Thank you. Thank you.
Anyway, what I'm saying is
that exes have this pain-in-the-ass way
of making you feel paranoid.
So, it's best
to avoid seeing them altogether.
Yes, but only if the past
has been fully resolved.
What do you mean?
Just that maybe there's
unfinished business with you and Carlo.
- [Eva] You crazy? It's been a year.
- They never talked about what happened.
- Because that makes it worse!
- Stop it!
No. That's enough
from both of you. We're over.
[both chuckle]
Okay, but admit it.
Okay. Admit what?
That you haven't settled everything
with you and Carlo.
[cell phone chimes]
GIULIA: I THINK
SHE WAS ENTHRALLED BY HIM TOO
DO SOMETHING!
What is it?
Nothing. Just stupid comments
from some coworkers.
- Okay. I'm gonna go. Bye.
- Well...
- See you later.
- Okay. You bet.
Uh, Carlo?
Margherita's opening is this evening.
[scoffs]
And I'm happy for her.
[patting] Bye, Marco.
Does that mean we can start, then?
- Absolutely. I'll leave you to it.
- Thanks.
PLISAR
PUBLISHING
[Luca] So? How's it going?
- [Carlo exclaims]
- A star on the rise, huh?
[chuckles]
We should wait for the data
from the sales, probably.
[Luca] You've gotten so pragmatic.
Hang on. I managed
to get us a big first-run
and two translations
in Spain and in France. Yeah?
I closed the deal today.
Ding, ding, ding, ding.
- Wow. That's great news, huh?
- For you, in particular.
[scoffs] For me?
Yes. You did a great job,
and it's gotten you a great opportunity.
What opportunity?
It's the office in Paris.
They want someone like you out there.
Someone like me?
[laughs]
They want you out there
keeping eyes on the French market,
finding other rare talent like Sofia.
New entries that can be translated then be
launched throughout the European market.
This could be big for you.
And if I'm not mistaken,
you speak French.
- No? Oui? Oui.
- Oui.
Oui. Très bien!
So then, will you accept it or not?
A job in Paris?
I mean, uh, Luca, I... I don't know.
I... I don't know. I need to...
[inhales sharply] I need to think
about it and get organized.
Uh, my home is Milan.
My friend,
you're up to your neck in quicksand here.
Work is going well, no doubting that,
but your relationship with any girl
just never lasts.
You still live
where you lived with Marghe.
Trust me.
Get on that plane.
[dramatic music playing]
I'll give you the week to decide.
[inaudible]
- Hi!
- [Anna] Hey.
Hi!
[Margherita] So?
How are you doing?
Uh, it's hurting a bit today.
I tossed and turned all night last night.
A LOVE AFFAIR
Oh. Thank you.
[chuckles]
You look a little tired yourself.
Yeah. I guess
I couldn't really sleep either.
- Mm.
- A million thoughts in my head.
Hmm.
Would you like to share
any of them with me?
With everything
that's changed this year, I...
uh, I'm not sure where to begin.
I know. It's been
a really intense year for you.
No need to go over it again.
Yes.
And today's a new beginning.
Wish me luck. Okay?
[chuckles] It'll be wonderful.
I know that it will.
I knew you could do it.
Thank you.
But tell me that more often.
["Before You Go" by Lewis Capaldi playing]
♪ I hate you, I hate you, I hate you
But I was just kidding myself ♪
♪ Our every moment, I start to replace ♪
♪ 'Cause now that they're gone
All I hear are the words I needed to say ♪
♪ When you hurt under the surface ♪
♪ Like troubled water running cold ♪
♪ Well, time can heal, but this won't ♪
♪ So, before you go ♪
♪ Was there something I... ♪
MARCELLO
SHALL I PICK YOU UP?
MARGHERITA:
NO, THANKS. THERE'S NO NEED.
SEE YOU THERE
♪ Before you go ♪
♪ Was there something I could've said
To make it all stop hurting? ♪
♪ It kills me how your mind
Can make you feel so worthless ♪
♪ So, before you go... ♪
Hi, nice to meet you.
I'm Silvia, his sister.
Nice to meet you. Sofia.
I've heard a lot about you. [chuckles]
Great.
Now I have to admit
I've already finished reading the book.
Yeah, but I thought it was great. Really.
Thank you.
♪ I start to replay ♪
♪ But all I can think about
Is seeing that look on your face ♪
♪ When you hurt under the surface ♪
♪ Like troubled water... ♪
[Carlo] I'm so glad
you were able to make it.
This is really incredible.
Yes, yes, yes.
I think it's all so incredible.
- Anyway, thanks for coming.
- [Silvia] No worries.
- So where's the author?
- This way.
Sofia, Paolo, my father,
and my mother, Loretta.
- Nice to meet you.
- [Sofia] Nice to meet you.
♪ Was there something I could've said
To make your heart beat better? ♪
♪ If only I'd have known
You had a storm to weather ♪
How are you doing?
- I'm okay.
- You ready for this?
I'm terrified!
It's all right. Let's just jump right in.
♪ Was there something I could've said
To make it all stop hurting? ♪
♪ It kills me how your mind
Can make you feel so worthless ♪
♪ So... ♪
[Carlo] Thank you all for coming.
Let's get started.
My name is Carlo Pentecoste.
SOFIA CASADEI
THE WAY THINGS ARE
THE AUTHOR WILL BE INTRODUCED
BY PUBLISHER CARLO PENTECOSTE
[Sofia] My novel recounts a true story.
Well, as much as a novel can.
I like to think that it's about
how we're often so close
to the solution that we're looking for,
but the solution scares us,
and so we choose to avoid it
and look elsewhere.
For years, I too avoided the truth
of a painful memory from my childhood.
I couldn't admit it to myself
or to anyone else.
I was avoiding the solution.
I was avoiding reality.
Thank you.
[audience applauding]
[Carlo] After all,
who here has never been faced
with, uh,
an uncomfortable and painful truth?
Uh, you talk in great length
about this broken link
that can, uh,
leave behind a dark space in us,
an empty space even,
filled with answerless questions.
But still you've managed
to fill this space with words of empathy.
And for those of us
who deal with writing or literature,
that is our most delicate
and powerful tool.
It's the only way we can look back
at where we've been
and look at what happened
when we got lost,
who we were being, who we've become,
and, above all,
how we can change our path for the future.
[audience applauding]
[dramatic music playing]
[inaudible]
[door closes]
STUDIO VERNA
INTERIOR ARCHITECTURE
[Margherita] Hi!
[Eva] Hey. It's about time!
Look who's here.
- [Eva chuckles]
- Hi.
Is everything okay?
We thought you weren't coming.
Yes. Sorry.
I changed my dress at the last minute.
I was feeling a little nervous.
- You look incredible.
- [Margherita] Thank you.
Wait. What's going on over here?
Can you come with me for a second, please?
I wanted to show you
some fabric that I love
and that I wanted to use
in the living room.
- Right now?
- Oh, yeah.
So what's this dress thing about?
What? Nothing.
You chose that dress two weeks ago. Hmm?
I took a little bit of a detour.
A little detour?
This yellow would be just perfect
for your living room.
That's violet.
Even better, then.
I'm gonna take off my coat.
Don't go anywhere.
[house music playing]
- Oh, there she is. You're gorgeous.
- You look spectacular.
[Sofia] I'll be right back.
- Oh, here she is. Our child prodigy!
- [Sofia] Hey.
- I'm gonna go get a refill. I'm empty.
- [Sofia chuckles]
- See you in a bit, Ada.
- See you later.
- She's very important.
- Oh, really?
Oh yes!
[both laugh]
Today is just the best day of my life.
By far.
Well, good.
You deserve it all.
You'll have to be my editor forever.
Why not? Although, it might be hard
to meet with me in person.
[Sofia] Why?
- [whispers] There's a chance I'm leaving.
- To where?
[Carlo] Paris.
Paris?
There's an office in Paris,
and I guess they want me there.
To new beginnings!
Yes, Luca, she's here.
He's looking for you.
Excuse me. Sofia, let me introduce you
to someone very important.
- [Sofia] Sure.
- [Luca] Come on.
Listen. Why don't you tell them
that story you told me earlier?
Excuse me, ladies and gentlemen.
Attention please.
[Eva] Yes. Because our girl,
Margherita, has a little speech to make.
- [Margherita] No! No!
- Yes.
- Over to you. Come on.
- [Margherita chuckles]
Fine! Okay.
[breathes deeply]
So, um,
I'd like to say
that I feel really confident
and I'm not even the least bit scared.
But I don't wanna lie!
[all laughing]
I am very scared.
I'm terrified, really.
[dramatic music playing]
Um,
for me, this studio represents a dream.
A dream that has been locked
in a drawer for far too long.
Actually, in a box.
[chuckles] No. I mean it because...
Well, 'cause one day I opened a box
filled with these old things of mine,
uh, they'd been forgotten.
Like my diploma,
notebooks from university
filled with ideas.
And that was the moment
I knew I was keeping the box open.
I knew that it had to bring me here today
with all of you, to... [chuckles]
...to celebrate a new start.
Because this is a new start for me.
Thank you.
I hope you all need to redecorate
your homes in the near future!
[all laughing]
And if you do, I hope
that you will think of me. [chuckles]
- [Giulia] Cheers!
- [all] Cheers!
[woman] Whoo!
[house music playing]
- [glass clatters]
- Thanks.
- Great party.
- Yeah. It is.
Every single person who matters is here.
Sorry. I'm hiding with you
because I don't know anyone here.
Well, I only know a quarter of the guests.
That's not counting the ones
I only know through email.
[Carlo chuckles]
You know, I wanted
to read Sofia's book, actually.
- Wait. Really?
- [Marco] Yes!
You want a free copy, don't you?
- [laughing]
- Oh. Come on!
No, I'll buy it. I'll buy it. I swear.
Yeah. You'd better. That goes
towards author and publishing rights.
Excuse me?
Can I get two jagers with lemon, please?
And they're on this guy over here.
No, no! Sorry. No, no, no, no. Just one.
[inaudible]
["Valse Sentimentale, No. 6, Op. 51
by Tchaikovsky playing]
Great. Marcello, this is Flavio.
- Hey. Nice to meet you.
- Nice to meet you too.
He's a big fan of yours.
I love your work very much.
And now I know
that you're a lucky man as well.
- Very!
- [cell phone ringing]
I'm sure you have a lot to talk about.
Just give me a minute.
[indistinct chatter]
Hello.
[Carlo] Hi.
I just wanted to say hi
and, um... and tell you
I'm sorry I'm not there.
Thanks.
I'm sorry too.
[Carlo] I can hear music.
What did you choose?
Don't you recognize it?
[Carlo] Tchaikovsky.
Of course.
It goes well with your studio.
You haven't seen it.
[Carlo] Well, I...
Uh, I'm trying to imagine it.
Let's see.
You've chosen bold colors for the walls,
an excellent selection of lamps.
So it's well lit.
That's true.
[Carlo] Ground floor,
big windows, so it gets
a lot of natural light during the day.
Right?
Uh, yeah.
That all was pretty predictable, though.
[Carlo] You're not wearing
a pant-suit. No jacket.
It's classy. Very elegant, I'd say.
Long, green dress.
Am I close?
You're good at imagining.
[Carlo] Concordia was the right address.
Even though we didn't know why.
[both chuckle]
Who lives there now?
A wonderful couple.
They always agree on everything.
[Carlo scoffs]
[inhales sharply] Dangerous situation.
[both chuckle]
Hey. What if I never mentioned it to you?
- What's that?
- Back at the college.
The misunderstanding.
Have you ever wondered?
I do, often.
[inhales deeply]
But even still,
it was never going to work with us.
Hmm.
[exhales]
[inhales sharply]
I've been thinking
about you a lot, you know?
I really try not to.
[chuckles]
Just can't help it.
Being together was important,
especially when we were apart.
[inhales deeply]
The changes I've gone through
since we broke it off,
you've inspired them.
[electro music playing]
That is the most beautiful thing
you could say.
[sighs]
[Carlo] You need to go back in.
- It's your party.
- Yes. Hmm.
[both chuckle lightly]
I know you're gonna do great.
Hmm.
So what now?
I don't know.
Let's see what you come up with.
LOOSELY BASED ON "FIDELITY"
BY MARCO MISSIROLI
[music fades]
[dramatic music playing]