A NETFLIX SERIES
["Un Giorno in Piu" playing]
[motorcycle engine revving]
[keys jangling]
[light switch clicks]
Marghe?
[keys clatter]
[microwave beeping]
[music playing over radio]
[dish clattering]
[door opening]
What happened? You're home late.
I was working.
I couldn't get rid of this one client.
He just kept asking questions.
[Carlo] You could've at least called.
I was starting to get worried.
I know. I'm sorry.
I meant to call you back, but...
Well, I mean, you know how it goes.
Uh, Eva asked me to make some calls and...
Well, then it got late.
[Carlo] Dinner's ready.
- I'll be right back. I'm gonna change.
- Mm-hmm.
[dramatic music playing]
[Margherita] I have to go.
[door slams]
Do you, though?
[door opens]
[footsteps receding]
You sure you're okay?
Yeah. Sure.
Just a little bit tired.
[mouse clicks]
[keyboard clacking]
So, listen, Marghe.
I had some new clients call about
the Concordia house again.
They said it's perfect,
it has everything they wanted.
I'm buying you time, though.
Thanks.
I know that you can't
just keep holding onto it.
You're not ready
to put an offer in. Are you?
No. We are, it's just
it depends on if Carlo's novel sells
I don't know when he'll be done.
Your communication is fantastic, truly.
[scoffs]
Yep.
[melancholy music playing]
Okay, look. All I'm saying
is if you two are having problems,
then maybe you should forget
about the house
and focus on your relationship.
You two need to communicate.
If he's not talking, then you need to.
And if something's going on,
don't hide it.
Not if you want him to be honest too.
- [phone ringing]
- Of course.
Excuse me.
Casa Futuro, Eva speaking.
How may I help you?
[Carlo] All right, kids.
Tomorrow's a big day.
You're gonna meet
important writers, editors,
and even some important publishers.
And to top it off,
there's a party afterwards.
- [students cheer]
- [Carlo] With an open bar.
- But you are staying sober.
- No!
- [students] Aww.
- Uh, yes. Actually you will.
Because the editors will drink.
That's good. Let them drink.
And encourage them, especially
if you want to hear those magic words,
"Email me some pages."
Trust me. Make the most of this occasion.
- Bye. See you.
- [students applauding]
[indistinct chatter]
Hi.
- Hey.
- How's it going?
It's okay.
And how's it going with your story?
I've started writing a little.
Oh. That's great.
- [Leonardo] See you later, teach.
- Have a good day.
- [Sofia] Bye.
- See you.
[dramatic music playing]
- [Carlo] Hi.
- Hey.
[door closes]
[music playing over radio]
Did you eat already?
Mm-hmm.
Yeah. It's incredible. I'm on fire today.
- I can't stop writing.
- Yeah.
[keys clatter]
Hey there.
Thanks.
Hey. How about we go out?
Um...
It's just that tonight
I wanted to focus on the book.
Is that okay?
Yeah. Go for it.
You know, the symposium is tomorrow.
I... I just wanted
to get a good amount done beforehand.
[keyboard clacking]
[groans, breathes deeply]
[laptop clatters]
[groans]
[cell phone vibrating]
[exhales]
[cell phone chimes]
ANDREA: I HOPE
I DIDN'T GET YOU IN ANY TROUBLE
MARGHERITA: NO, DON'T WORRY.
YOU DIDN'T DO ANYTHING.
I DON'T UNDERSTAND ANYTHING ANYMORE
[faucet running]
ANDREA: DO YOU WANT TO HANG OUT AGAIN?
[dramatic music playing]
[groans, sighs]
[cell phone clicks]
[indistinct chatter]
[Carlo] Good morning!
[tense music playing]
"ALL LITERATURE IS AN ASSAULT
ON THE FRONTIER." FRANZ KAFKA
[door creaking]
You wanted all of this. Now it's yours.
[water bubbling]
[groans]
- [exhales]
- [packing tape tearing]
[Margherita] Good morning.
What time is it?
[Margherita] It's late.
I let you sleep in.
- You making progress?
- I am.
I gotta make a decision
if I wanna keep all this old stuff.
Were you having a nightmare?
Huh?
Before you woke up,
you just shouted, "I can't! No!"
[Carlo] Huh.
Uh, yeah. I...
I, uh,
sort of had a nightmare. I guess.
And you?
You sleep okay?
Uh, you know...
It's hard to sleep without you.
Hmm.
Oh, look.
My notes from back in college. [sighs]
[Carlo] Huh.
And old designs.
It's so stupid.
- You want some help?
- No, no. I've got it.
- That's a lot to unpack.
- And it's all mine.
Yeah, but, I mean,
you could do it with me.
Look. Sometimes I need my space.
[cup clatters]
[Carlo] Okay.
I'll get out of your way, then.
Carlo, don't get offended.
I'm not. It's fine.
[Margherita] You're not
gonna take a shower first?
[Carlo exhales sharply]
It's broken.
["Home" by Max Jury playing]
♪ Home, my home ♪
♪ All the makers mark ♪
♪ Has made its mark on me ♪
♪ And the cold, gray fog ♪
THE MEMORY OF A WONDERFUL DAY
♪ On the interstate ♪
THE DAY OF MY GRADUATION
♪ Always cover me ♪
MILAN POLYTECHNIC UNIVERSITY
AWARDS MARGHERITA VERNA
A MASTER'S DEGREE WITH HONORS
IN ARCHITECTURE
♪ I'm a long, long way ♪
♪ Oh, I'll be back someday ♪
♪ From home ♪
[keys jangling]
[sighs]
I picked up the new part for the shower.
I'll go work on it.
Okay.
What's going on?
What is all this?
Love-letter postcards
between my dad and another woman.
Franco.
[Carlo sighs]
Maybe it was...
Well, I don't know, nothing romantic.
He had a relationship with her.
They wrote to each other for years.
My father was having an affair...
and I didn't know about it.
[scoffs]
I'm so sorry.
I don't know
how I'm gonna tell my mom about it.
I mean, it was such a long time ago.
You father's passed on.
Maybe you shouldn't.
[Margherita inhales, exhales]
Doesn't she have a right to know?
[Carlo sighs]
Let's go out tonight. Huh?
- I think that you can really use a break.
- [sighs]
Hmm?
Okay.
[Marco] If only it was that easy.
[Giulia] I'm not saying that it's easy.
- [jazz music playing]
- Sure. Hey!
- [Giulia] Hi.
- [Margherita] Hey.
[Marco] You guys here for dinner?
Yeah. Uh, we were just gonna grab a table.
What? No. Sit with us.
- No.
- [Carlo] We don't want to interrupt.
Are you kidding? Come on, sit.
I'll get you some wine.
Uh, Beppe?
Can we get two more glasses of the red?
Thank you.
[Carlo] Well, how's it going?
I was just reminiscing here with Giulia.
We were talking
about our first date, actually.
Where was your first date?
It was at a Thai place.
I asked Marghe
what she wanted for dinner, and she said,
"Ethnic food."
So, I decided I was gonna surprise her
and take her out for Thai.
How was it?
Disgusting.
[all laughing]
But I lied and said Thai was my favorite.
Huh. She's never told me that.
[Giulia] You two are amazing.
You're always discovering
new things about each other.
- [Carlo chuckles]
- Well, that's not always a positive thing.
You're right. One, zero.
All I'm saying
is that you two are a very strong couple.
We came here on our first date,
and now it's our place.
I mean, that is the reason
that I bought it, was for us.
Now it's two, zero.
That's not all. On our first date,
we also went to a Cezanne exhibition.
[laughs]
Uh, well, I pretended
I knew everything about the art, and all,
because it was our first date
and I wanted to win her over.
- And I immediately knew.
- You didn't buy it.
Not even for a minute.
But I still dragged him
to every exhibition that I could find
just to see how much he cared about me.
Hmm. No.
That was just the work of a cynical woman,
who always gets whatever she wants
by cruelly exercising her power.
Three, zero.
You're right. I am cynical.
Or maybe I was cynical.
But now, after the mistakes I've made,
I realized that, actually,
cynicism is a way to hide that
you really feel pathetic.
Three to one?
I guess. Three to one. Yeah.
[Carlo] Let's toast.
You have catching up to do.
Drink, drink. We got this. Drink!
[chuckles]
They sure have quite the stories,
don't they?
[motorcycle engine revving]
[indistinct chatter]
I'm sorry. I was hoping
this would distract you for a bit.
[sighs] It wasn't a good night for this.
[sniffles]
But it's hard to be distracted
when everything's falling apart. You know?
[Carlo] Come on.
Don't blow this out of proportion.
Franco and Anna
were married right to the end. All right?
So, they must have been happy together.
Sure. By hiding the truth
from one another.
Oh, what do we know
about what they did or didn't hide?
I can't do this anymore, Carlo. I mean it.
I can't keep pretending everything's fine,
and that we're the happiest couple
in the world and...
- [Carlo] What's that got to do with this?
- You do whatever you want. And I...
And you? What is it?
I've thought about you,
and you alone, for five years.
"Will he ever get his book done?"
"Does he have enough space to work?"
"How can I be more supportive to Carlo?"
"Is he comfortable?"
And anything that mattered to me,
all of the goals, ambitions, or plans,
they get pushed aside for you.
Then I wake up one morning
and find you'd rather be
with some 20-year-old kid instead of me.
- Let that go!
- [Margherita] And I've done nothing wrong!
Marghe, some 20-year-old
isn't taking your place!
My God. Admit it, Carlo.
You know what this is?
I think you're still upset
because of that crazy misunderstanding.
Just drop it, Marghe!
Not everything is about you,
but you always think it is.
You're fucking selfish,
self-referencing, self-centered,
really any word that begins with "self."
You choose which one. You're the writer!
The real misunderstanding is you and me.
[scoffs]
[melancholy music playing]
[indistinct chatter]
[Luca] There he is!
Did you come to see some real writers?
Because we have quite the lineup.
[sighs] Luca, I am not in the mood
to be lectured by you today.
- Do you wanna get a coffee?
- I'm on my fifth one.
No better drug around.
Shit! I forgot my wallet.
Really? That old excuse?
[Carlo] Oh, come on. Just buy me a coffee.
Anyway, you're right.
It's been pretty hard.
I've been distracted.
Yeah. You look like shit,
now that you point it out.
I've been on the couch for two nights.
Whose choice was that? Tell me.
[Carlo] Doesn't matter.
I have been writing, though.
[Luca] Good!
Maybe you need some chaos. Okay?
I mean, what if you created the mess
to inspire your writing?
That your new pickup line?
You're a psychotherapist now? Come on.
[Luca chuckles]
Look. I wish I knew what to say,
but I don't.
I mean, getting married?
No. Other people can do that.
Your block is when?
In one hour. Just down the hallway.
Well, we'd better go see
who's stealing my thunder.
Oh.
Wanna sniff out the competition, huh?
- Hmm.
- Come with me.
[Luca chuckles]
My desire...
It was actually quite bold,
my magnificent desire.
I think that's what's lead me
through the streets of my life,
and through my pages too.
This desire to do something different,
and this deep desire I had
to forge a new path.
- I don't know where the desire comes from...
- Look at that guy.
That big-headed asshole's
already sold a million copies.
- I hate to admit it, but he's pretty good.
- [Luca] He is.
[man]... would pull me out of class.
He'd take me to the beach or to the park,
and we'd spend entire days
imagining worlds
of elves and fairies dancing in the wind.
[dramatic music playing]
So there she is.
That's who you're talking about.
- Hey.
- I mean, she is very beautiful.
[man] ...I've thought about them often.
I love this rhetoric,
the rhetoric of desire.
[girl] That man's great.
- See you later, then, Carlo. Yeah.
- [Carlo] See you.
- See you later, professor.
- [Carlo] See you later.
Open bar?
[Carlo] There is,
but don't overdo it. I mean it.
Hey. Nice shirt, by the way.
Hey. Thanks.
[Luca] My friend,
culture won't put food on the table.
[chuckles]
Isn't it bad to eat all that fruit?
No. Because... Excuse me.
[cell phone vibrating]
Sorry. I'll be right back.
Hey. Hold my seat. I'll make this fast.
Yeah.
Oh. Hi. What's up?
[soft rock music playing]
[indistinct chatter]
[man] I'm just saying that we can change
your course schedule around.
And instead, start with ceramics.
- What do you think?
- [woman] I agree.
Perfect.
[Margherita] Hi.
[Anna] Hey.
How are you, honey? How's it going?
[scoffs] I'm okay. You?
[Anna] I'm fine.
The room's almost ready, you know?
Your father would've gone crazy
if he'd been here to see this.
Yeah. He always wanted things his way.
[Anna] Well, I don't want
to bother you. It's dinner time.
No. It's no problem, really.
Carlo isn't here.
[Anna] Oh. Where is he tonight?
A Symposium at the university.
They were having a party, I guess.
[Anna] And you're sitting at home
feeling sorry for yourself?
Get up! You can't just mope on the couch.
- Who said I was on the couch?
- [Anna laughs]
Look. Why don't you go and surprise him?
Maybe.
["Pass This On" by The Knife playing]
♪ I'm in love... ♪
[Carlo] Can I get a gin and tonic?
♪ What's his name? ♪
♪ I thought I'd come by to see him again ♪
♪ When you to dance ♪
♪ Oh, what a dance ♪
♪ When you to love ♪
♪ Oh, what a love ♪
♪ Does he mention my age, love? ♪
♪ Or is he more into young girls... ♪
- Here you go.
- [Carlo] Thanks.
♪ I'm in love with your brother ♪
♪ I thought I'd come by ♪
[cell phone chimes]
SOFIA
YOU DANCING?
♪ I'm in love with your brother ♪
♪ Yes I am ♪
♪ But maybe I shouldn't ask for his name ♪
CARLO: ME AND YOU DANCING
WHILE EVERYONE'S WATCHING?
♪ And you laugh ♪
♪ Oh, what a laugh ♪
♪ Does he know what I do? ♪
♪ And you'll pass this on, won't you ♪
♪ And if I asked him once
What would he say? ♪
♪ Does he know what I do? ♪
♪ And you'll pass this on, won't you? ♪
♪ And if I asked him once
What would he say? ♪
♪ Is he willing? ♪
[girl] This is my third round,
so I won't be in class tomorrow.
[inaudible]
- [Carlo] Are you having fun?
- [girl] Yeah.
[Carlo] Yeah? Okay.
Okay. Bye.
♪ Pass this on ♪
[song fades]
[tense music playing]
[Leonardo] What's the matter with you?
You're acting crazy as fuck!
[Sofia] Look. I think
you should just go. Leave me alone.
- [Leonardo] I should go?
- [Sofia] Yes! Go away!
- [Leonardo] You're crazy! I'm going.
- [Sofia] Go!
Bye.
[engine turning over]
[vespa engine revving]
[driver] All right.
This is it. That'll be 20 even.
Is everything okay?
Can we go somewhere?
Sure.
[Margherita] Are you sure
this is the right address?
[driver] According to the GPS, it is.
I can bring you
somewhere else if you'd like.
No. Never mind. Here's good.
[paper rustling]
Thank you.
It wasn't till I saw you with him
that I even knew you liked the kid.
There's a lot that you fail to notice.
You only see
what you wanna see, I suppose.
So you were trying to provoke me before?
I wasn't very successful.
No. You were. I promise.
- [Carlo] Where are you going?
- Come on!
[gate rattles]
Sofia, what are you doing?
The park's closed.
There are cameras all over the place.
Stay there then, if you want.
[exhales sharply]
[motorcycle engine revving]
[electro music playing]
[indistinct chatter]
[chatter growing louder]
[electro music building]
[man] Hey! You're weak!
[crowd shouting]
Go on! Get in there!
[fighters grunting]
[grunting]
[Andrea grunts]
[fighter groaning]
[both fighters grunting]
Yeah! Yeah! Come on. Strangle him!
[birds warbling]
[Sofia] Boo!
[Carlo exhales]
Why is it
that we always end up in a park. Huh?
Yet we never move forward.
Where did you have your first kiss?
I don't know.
Um, I can't remember.
I had mine on a slide.
I was in middle school,
and I can't remember the kid's name.
[chuckles]
- Classic middle school romance.
- Hmm.
- I've never been in love before.
- No?
It's never been easy for me.
[dramatic music playing]
It isn't for anyone.
No. For me, it's worse.
I just don't know how to trust.
I didn't trust you at first.
But now...
It's just some kind of miracle.
You're here.
[helmet clatters]
Not what you were expecting. Was it?
Admittedly, when I got the address,
I expected more of a restaurant or a bar.
Something in that vein.
Yeah. I thought you would.
Let's go.
Where? The hospital?
It's just a scratch. Okay?
Come on.
[Margherita] Are you sure you're okay?
I'm okay.
Okay, but you can't drive like this.
I'm calling a taxi.
So you still don't trust me yet?
[Carlo exhales]
[Sofia] Do you and I
both want the same thing?
We don't.
I can't do this.
Not in the way I want to.
Here.
It's my story. I wanted to give it to you.
I can't be here in Milan with you.
I'm leaving for good.
I won't see you again.
[footsteps receding]
[sighs]
[sniffles]
[radio host] And, you know,
this is a group that...
I mean, this is back when I was 12,
I... I didn't know
the slightest thing about them,
but they were all from Chicago
and they had already created a lot of buzz
over the hit song "Are You My Woman?"
Which is what we were just listening to.
[Stavo pensando a te" playing]
[grunts]
[exhales sharply]
[car door opening]
[whispers] Oh shit.
[car door closes]
POLICE
[officer] What were you doing in the park?
Uh,
I mean, just walking.
- Is that so?
- Yeah.
ID, please.
[exhales] I don't have it.
I left it at home. I don't have it.
CARLO
INCOMING CALL
[both breathing heavily]
["Stavo pensando a te" continues playing]
LOOSELY BASED ON "FIDELITY"
BY MARCO MISSIROLI
[song ends]
[dramatic music playing]
[music fades]